…って そんなｱﾆﾒだっけ？＞
ﾎﾞｸ 志村 新八と 神楽ちゃん｡
ひょんなことから
働くことになった➡
その名は 坂田 銀時｡
侍は 衰退の一途をたどっていた｡
甘党 ｱﾝﾄﾞ 無鉄砲な
この男の営む 万事屋で➡
ﾎﾞｸら 万事屋３人で
腐った江戸を 一刀両断！
そんな時代に
侍魂をもった男が１人｡
(新八)＜侍の国… 僕らの国が
そう呼ばれたのは 今は 昔の話｡
20年前 突如 宇宙から舞い降りた
天人の台頭と 廃刀令により➡
The land of the samurai.
There was a time, long ago, when our country was called by that name.
With the arrival of the "Amanto" from outer space
and the Sword Ban twenty years ago, the samurai class fell into decline.
In such hard times, there was one man left with the spirit of the samurai.
His name is Gintoki Sakata, a reckless Jack of All Trades with a sweet tooth.
Due to some rather unexpected events, I,
Shinpachi Shimura, and Kagura, ended up working here.
The three of us slice up a corrupt Edo.
Wait, is that really the story?
[A fateful reunion with an old friend!! Gintoki's hidden past.]
[By the way, can you spell out "Anti-Foreigner Faction" without looking it up?]
[Odd Jobs Gin]
(銀時)おい ｺﾗ～｡
Hey!
ｵﾚが 以前から買いだめしていた
大量のﾁｮｺが 姿を消した｡
The huge stash of chocolate I was saving has disappeared.
食べたﾔﾂは 正直に 手 挙げろ｡
Whoever ate it, raise your hand now,
今なら
４分の３殺しで許してやる｡
and I'll only kill you three-fourths of the way.
４分の３って…
ほとんど死んでんじゃないすか｡
Three-fourths?
That's pretty much dead.
っていうか
ｱﾝﾀ いいかげんにしないと➡
Besides, if you don't cut it out, you really will get diabetes.
ﾎﾝﾄ 糖尿になりますよ｡
Another embassy attacked... serial terrorist bombings rampage continues.
(神楽)｢またも狙われた大使館｡
連続爆破事件 凶行 続く｣
物騒な世の中ｱﾙな～｡
私 恐いよ ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ ﾏﾐｰ｡
The world sure is violent place. Poppy, Mommy, I'm scared.
恐いのは ｵﾒｴだよ｡
You're the scary one.
幸せそうに
鼻血 たらしやがって！
Looking so happy with your bloody nose.
うまかったか？ ｵﾚのﾁｮｺは｡
Were my chocolates tasty?
A nosebleed from eating chocolate?
ﾁｮｺ食べて鼻血なんて そんなﾍﾞﾀな｡
Puh-leese!
とぼけんな～!! 鼻血から
糖分のにおいが ﾌﾟﾝﾌﾟﾝ ﾌﾟ～ﾝ！
Don't play dumb! I can smell the sugar in your blood!
Don't be silly.
ﾊﾞｶ言うな｡ ちょっと
鼻ｸｿ 深追いしただけよ｡
I just went in for a booger a little too deep.
年頃の娘が そんなに
深追いするわけねえだろ！
[MIND YOUR SUGAR LEVELS]
No girl your age would do that.
定年間近のﾃﾞｶか お前は！
What are you, a cop who's just about to retire?
例えが わかんねえよ！
っていうか 落ち着け!!
What kind of nonsense talk is that?
Anyway, chill out!
≪ぐわぁっ!!
(激突音)
What's the ruckus?
なんだなんだ？ おい｡
事故か？
An accident?
["Make Friends You Can Call by Their Nicknames, Even When You're an Old Fart"]
Hey!
(お登勢)ｺﾗｧ～～!!
Moron!  What are you doing, crashing into my shop?!
ﾜﾚ 人の店に
何してくれとんじゃ！
死ぬ覚悟 できてんだろうなぁ？
I hope you're ready to die!
(飛脚)す… すみません｡
S-Sorry. I didn't sleep well last night.
昨日から
あんまり寝てなかったもんで…｡
No problem! I'm gonna make sure you close your eyes forever!
よっしゃ！
今 永遠に 眠らせたらぁ!!
Otose! You shouldn't do that to an injured person!
お登勢さん！
ｹｶﾞ人相手に そんな！
大丈夫ですか？
(飛脚)へ… へい…｡
Are you all right?
Y-Yeah...
こりゃ ひどいや｡
神楽ちゃん 救急車 呼んで｡
This is bad. Kagura, call an ambulance.
救急車～!!
Ambulance!
誰が そんな
原始的な呼び方しろっつったよ!?
That's a pretty primitive way of calling an ambulance?!
You're a postman, huh? Your packages are a mess!
飛脚か ｱﾝﾀ｡
届けもん ｴﾗｲことになってんぞ｡
Th-This...
(飛脚)こ… これ…｡
これを… ｵﾚの代わりに
届けてください…｡
Deliver this in my place...
お願い…｡
Please...
(飛脚)なんか
大事な届け物らしくて➡
I think it's important.
届け損なったら
ｵﾚ ｸﾋﾞになっちゃうかも…｡
If I fail to deliver it... I might lose my job!
(飛脚)お願いします…！
Please...I beg you.
お おい…｡
Hey!
ここで合ってんだよなぁ？
You're sure this is the place?
うん｡
大使館？
Yup.
An embassy.
これ 戌威星の大使館ですよ！
This is the Inui Embassy!
戌威族っていったら
地球に最初に来た天人ですよね｡
The Inui from the Dog Star System were the first Amanto to come to earth, weren't they?
あぁ｡ 江戸城に 大砲 ﾌﾞﾁ込んで➡
Yeah.
They're the scary ones who fired cannons at the Edo Castle and forced the country to open up.
開国しちまった
おっかねえﾔﾂらだ｡
嫌なとこに来ちゃったなぁ おい｡
This is a nasty place, that's for sure.
Hey!
(天人)おい！ こんなところで
何やってんだ？ ﾃﾒｴら｡
What the hell are you doing here?
食われてえのかﾜﾝ？
Do you want to get eaten?
いや… ﾎﾞｸらは
届け物を頼まれただけで…｡
Well, we were just asked to deliver a package.
ほら 神楽 早く…｡
Come on, Kagura, hand it over...quick!
ﾁｯﾁｯﾁ… おいで ﾜﾝちゃん
酢ｺﾝﾌﾞあげるよ｡
Come 'ere, little doggy.
I'll give you some pickled seaweed.
What're you doing?!
あぁ… これだ これ｡
Here it is.
(天人)届けもんが来るなんて話
聞いてねえなぁ｡
Didn't hear anything about a package today.
最近は ただでさえ
爆弾事件 警戒して➡
Lately we've been worried about bombings.
厳戒態勢なんだ｡ 帰れ！
Security's tight. Go home.
ﾄﾞｯｸﾞﾌｰﾄﾞかもしんねえぞ｡
もらっとけって｡
It might be dog food inside. Enjoy.
(天人)そんなもん食うか！
Who'd eat crap like that?
(爆発音)
なんか よくわかんねえけど…➡
I don't really know what happened, but I think I know our next move.
するべきことは よくわかるよ｡
Run!
逃げろ～！
ｺﾗｧ 待て～!!
Hey, wait!
うぉっ！
ぐぉっ！
うっ！
Shinpachi! What the hell do you think you're doing? Let go!
新八～！ ﾃﾒｴ どういうつもりだ!?
離しやがれ!!
嫌だ！ １人で捕まるのは!!
No way! They're not taking me alone!
ｵﾚのことは構わず行け！ とか
言えねえのか お前は！
Can't you say something like, "Leave me. Just go on ahead"?
Think about me and just go to the next world!
私に構わず あの世へ逝って！
Shut up! I'm taking you with me!
黙れ！ お前の魂も連れていく!!
(天人たち)何事だ～!?
What's going on?!
あぁ～！ ﾜﾝ公 いっぱい来た～!!
Waah!  A pack of dog guards!
♪♪～
(桂)手間のかかるﾔﾂだ｡
These guys are a pain in the butt.
♪♪～
ほじぃっ!!
あ…｡
♪♪～
(桂)逃げるぞ 銀時｡
Time to go, Gintoki.
You're Zura!
お前… ﾂﾞﾗか！ ﾂﾞﾗ 小太郎か？
Kotaro Zura?!
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない！ 桂だぁ～!!
It's not Zura. It's Katsura!
あぁっ！
ﾃ ﾃﾒｴ！
Y-You bastard.
久しぶりに会ったのに
ｱｯﾊﾟｰｶｯﾄはないんじゃないの？
How long has it been since we last saw each other?
You didn't have to uppercut me, did you?
そのﾆｯｸﾈｰﾑで呼ぶのはやめろ と
何度も言ったはずだ｡
I've told you a thousand times to stop using that nickname.
つうか お前
なんで こんなところに？
Anyway, what are you doing here?
いつまで
くっちゃべってんだ ｺﾗｧ！
How long are you going to keep talking?!
Save it, Gintoki.
話はあとだ 銀時！
ﾁｯ｡
Wait!
(天人)待て ｺﾗ～！
He finally exposed himself.
(土方)とうとう
しっぽ 出しやがった｡
(土方)ﾌｯ…｡ 山崎！
Yamazaki!
(山崎)はっ｡
なんとしても➡
Yes!
Track down their base, at all cost.
ﾔﾂらの拠点 おさえてこい｡
はい！
Sir!
(土方)天人との戦で
活躍した英雄も➡
With all the Amanto in the world now, even the hero of the Amanto war is just another criminal.
天人様々の 今の世の中じゃ
ただの反乱分子か｡
(土方)この ご時世に
天人を追っ払おうなんざ➡
Takes real guts to still be fighting the Amanto these days.
大した夢想家だよ｡
(土方)おい 沖田 起きろ｡
Hey, Okita, wake up.
I'm surprised that you could sleep through that explosion.
(土方)お前 よく
あの爆音のなか 寝てられるな｡
(沖田)爆音って…｡
Explosion? Did you let the terrorists attack again?
また 爆弾犯
防げなかったんですかい？
何やってんだよ 土方さん
ﾏｼﾞﾒに働けよ｡
What's your problem, Hijikata?  You need to apply yourself.
(土方)もう１回 眠るか？ ｺﾗ｡
You wanna sleep permanently?
天人の館が いくら吹っ飛ぼうが
知ったこっちゃねえよ｡
They can blow up all the Amanto for all I care.
連中を泳がして
雁首 揃ったところを➡
I'll let those fishies swim for a bit before I'll reel 'em in, line 'em up...and cut their necks.
まとめて たたき斬ってやる｡
真選組の晴れ舞台だぜ｡
楽しいｹﾝｶになりそうだ｡
It'll be a proud moment for the Shinsengumi.
I'm looking forward to this fight.
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)またしても
天人の大使館を狙った➡
Another Amanto embassy has been bombed.
爆弾事件が 発生しました｡
Our reporter Ketsuno is on the scene!
それでは 現場から
伝えてもらいましょう｡
Ketsuno, you there?
現場の結野さん！ 結野ｱﾅ！
Ketsuno! Ana!
(結野)はい 現場の結野です｡
This is Ketsuno at the scene.
[Announcer Ketsuno]
[No Entry]
This time, the despicable bomber has gone after the Dog Star embassy.
今回 卑劣な爆弾魔に狙われた
戌威星大使館｡
幸い 死傷者は
出ていませんが… えっ？
Luckily, nobody has been injured or killed.
あっ 新しい情報が入りました！
We've just received word
that the alleged terrorists were caught on tape by a security camera.
監視ｶﾒﾗに
犯人と思われる一味が…｡
(結野)あぁ～ ﾊﾞｯﾁﾘ映ってますね！
Ah... You can see them very clearly!
ﾎﾝﾄに ﾊﾞｯﾁﾘ映っちゃってるよ…｡
You really can see us clearly.
What'll I do? Sis is going to kill me.
どうしよう… 姉上に殺される｡
I'm on TV. I've got to call home.
ﾃﾚﾋﾞ出演！ 実家に電話しなきゃ｡
何かの陰謀ですかね？ こりゃ｡
なんで ﾎﾞｸらが こんな目に…｡
Do you suppose this is all some sort of conspiracy?
How did we get into this mess?
唯一 桂さんに会えたのが
不幸中の幸いでしたよ｡
Meeting Katsura was the only good that came out of it.
こんな状態のﾎﾞｸら
かくまってくれるなんて…｡
To think he'd actually hide us during all this.
Gin, he's friend of yours, isn't he?
銀さん 知り合いなんですよね？
いったい どういう人なんですか？
What sort of person is he?
ん～… 爆弾魔｡
Hmm... A terrorist.
はい？
Stop using that word, Gintoki.
(桂)そんな言い方は よせ 銀時｡
(桂)我々は 爆弾魔などではない｡
We're not terrorists.
我々は 攘夷志士だ！
We're Freedom Fighters!
[Special Police - Shinsengumi Garrison]
(近藤)へぇ～ とうとう
しっぽをつかんだってのか？
Oh? So we finally found them?
あぁ｡ 今 山崎が 後を追ってる｡
Yes. Yamazaki is following them right now.
ﾔﾂらのｱｼﾞﾄが割れるのも
時間の問題だ 近藤さんよ｡
It's only a matter of time before we discover their base, Kondo.
(近藤)そうか…｡
ご苦労だったな ﾄｼ｡
I see... Good work, Toshi.
ねぎらいの言葉は まだ早いぜ｡
It's too soon to thank me.
すべては ﾔﾂらを
たたき斬ってからだ｡
Save it for after we've killed them!
そうだったな｡
That's right.
真選組の誉れは
武勲でのみ あげることができる｡
The Shinsengumi only give credit after distinguished military service.
We, the Shinsengumi, belong in battle.
戦いの中こそが
ｵﾚたち真選組の居場所だ｡
ﾌﾝ… ｵﾚは
局長のｱﾝﾀに ついてくだけだ｡
You're the chief. I'm only following orders.
任せたぞ ﾄｼ｡
I'm counting on you, Toshi!
(土方)あぁ｡
Yup.
(山崎)入り口に
殺気立った野郎が２人｡
There are two scary-looking guys at the entrance.
ﾌｯ 間違いねえ｡ 見つけたぜ｡
No doubt about it, we've found them.
Say, Mom, is that man a peeping tom?
(男の子)ねぇ お母さん
あの人 覗き？
(母親)ｼｯ｡ ﾕｳちゃんは
あんな大人になっちゃﾀﾞﾒよ｡
Shh! Yu, you mustn't grow up to be like that.
(男)警察に通報したほうが
いいんじゃねえか？
Shouldn't we report him to the police?
(山崎)えぇ～…？
この国を汚す害虫 天人を
打ち払い➡
The Amanto are pests that pollute this country with their presence.
もう一度 侍の国を立て直す｡
We must force them out and rebuild this country into the land of samurai once more.
(桂)我々が行うは
国を守るがための攘夷だ｡
We're expelling foreigners in order to protect this country.
攘夷志士だって!?
何じゃそらよ？
Foreigner expulsion patriotism?!
What's that?
Foreigner Expulsion is an ideology that sprang up during the Amanto attacks twenty years ago.
攘夷とは 20年前の
天人襲来のときに起きた➡
They tried to drive out the aliens.
宇宙人を排そうとする思想で➡
The Amanto pressured us to open up our doors.
高圧的に開国を迫ってきた天人に
危機感を感じた侍は➡
Under that threat, the samurai rose up together to try to chase them out of Edo.
彼らを 江戸から追い払おうと
一斉蜂起して 戦ったんだ｡
♪♪～
でも… 天人の強大な力を見て
弱腰になった幕府は➡
Confronted by Amanto's immense power, the government surrendered.
侍たちを置き去りに 勝手に
天人と 不平等な条約を締結｡
They abandoned the samurai and signed an unfair treaty with the Amanto.
幕府の中枢を握った天人は
侍たちから 刀を奪い➡
The Amanto had control over the core of the government. They took away the samurai's swords
彼らを無力化していったんだ｡
and made them powerless.
その後…➡
I heard that afterwards
主だった攘夷志士は
大量粛清されたって聞いたけど➡
many of the exclusionists were purged.
まだ残ってたなんて…｡
I never thought that they still existed.
どうやら ｵﾚたちは
踊らされたらしいな｡
え？
It seems we've been manipulated.
Isn't that right, Mr. Postman?
なぁ おい 飛脚のあんちゃんよ｡
あっ ﾎﾝﾄね！
あのｹﾞｼﾞｹﾞｼﾞﾏﾕ ﾃﾞｼﾞｬｳﾞ！
He's right! I remember those bushy eyebrows.
どういうことですか ｹﾞｼﾞｹﾞｼﾞさん！
Hold on. What's going on, bushy-brows?!
全部 ﾃﾒｴの仕業か？ 桂｡
It's all your doing, isn't it, Katsura?
All these recent attacks that have everyone in a panic.
最近 世を騒がす事件も
今回のことも｡
ﾌﾝ… たとえ 汚い手を使おうとも
手に入れたいものがあったのさ｡
There was something I had to get my hands on, even if it meant dirtying them.
銀時… この腐った国を
立て直すため➡
Gintoki, will you take up your sword alongside me in order to rebuild this corrupt country?
再び ｵﾚとともに 剣をとらんか？
(桂)白夜叉と恐れられた お前の力
再び 貸してくれ｡
Once again, will you lend me the strength that made you feared as the White Knight?
♪♪～
銀時… この腐った国を
立て直すため➡
Gintoki, will you take up your sword alongside me in order to rebuild this corrupt country?
再び ｵﾚとともに 剣をとらんか？
(桂)白夜叉と恐れられた
お前の力…➡
Once again will you lend me the strength that made you feared as the White Knight?
再び 貸してくれ！
♪♪～
This is the end of the line.
((桂:これまでか…｡
敵の手に かかるより➡
Rather than be caught by the enemy, let us finish as warriors and slash our bellies.
最期は武士らしく
潔く腹を切ろう｡
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえよ！ 立て｡
Don't be stupid.
Stand up.
If you've got enough time to fantasize about your beautiful death,
美しく最期を飾りつける
暇があるなら➡
最期まで…
美しく生きようじゃねえか！
why don't you live your life beautifully to the end?
♪♪～
Let's do this, Zura.
いくぜ ﾂﾞﾗ！
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ！
It's not Zura. It's Katsura!
(銀時/桂)うお～！))
His white hair was soaked in blood.
(桂)その男
銀色の髪に血を浴び➡
戦場を駆る姿は まさしく夜叉｡
Bounding into battle was a vision of a demon knight in full glory.
天人との戦において 鬼神のごとき
働きを やってのけ➡
It was he who fought like an avenging angel in the war with Amanto...
敵はおろか
味方からも恐れられた武神➡
He was like a god of war who was feared not only by his enemies but by his own people.
坂田 銀時！
Gintoki Sakata, you should join with us, once again, to fight against the Amanto.
我らと ともに
再び天人と戦おうではないか！
銀さん… 攘夷戦争に
参加してたんですか？
Gin...you were involved in the Foreigner Expulsion War too?
戦が終わるとともに
姿を消したがな｡
He disappeared after the battle.
お前の考えることは
昔から よくわからん｡
I never really knew what was going on in your head.
ｵﾚは 派手なｹﾝｶは 好きだが➡
I like a nice loud fight, but I hate morbid crap like terrorism.
そういう 辛気臭ぇのは嫌いなの！
ｵﾚたちの戦は
もう終わったんだよ｡
The battle is over.
それを いつまでも ﾈﾁﾈﾁ ﾈﾁﾈﾁ…｡
姑か お前は！
How long are you going to go on and on?
What are you, my mother-in-law?
ﾊﾞｶか 貴様は！
おなごは みんな ﾈﾁﾈﾁしている！
Are you stupid?!
Mothers always pester their sons.
そういう すべてを含めて
包み込む度量がないから➡
Nobody likes you because your heart isn't big enough to embrace.
貴様は ﾓﾃないんだ！
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
You little...
If I didn't have naturally wavy hair I'd definitely be popular with girls. I think.
ｵﾚが もし 天然ﾊﾟｰﾏじゃなかったら
ﾓﾃﾓﾃだぞ！ たぶん｡
There you go again blaming everything on your naturally wavy hair.
何でも天然ﾊﾟｰﾏのせいにして
自己を保っているのか｡
Pathetic.
悲しい男だ｡
悲しくなんかないわ！
Who's pathetic?
人は ｺﾝﾌﾟﾚｯｸｽをﾊﾞﾈにして➡
People use their complexes as springboards to greatness.
より高みを…｡
ｱﾝﾀら！ なんの話してんの！
What the hell are you talking about?!
うっ！
ううっ… ぐえ！
ｵﾚたちの戦は
まだ終わってなどいない｡
Our fight is far from over.
貴様の中にとて
まだ残っていよう… 銀時｡
Inside, you're still fighting, Gintoki.
(桂)国を憂い ともに戦った
仲間の命を奪っていった➡
You worry about this country and are angry at the government and the Amanto for taking the lives of
幕府と天人に対する 怨嗟の念が！
the people who fought with you.
♪♪～
Let's clear out the Amanto and rebuild this corrupt country.
天人を掃討し
この腐った国を 立て直す｡
我ら 生き残った者が➡
It's the only way we can honor the memory of our dead.
死んでいったﾔﾂらに
してやれるのは それぐらいだろ！
(桂)我らの
次なる攘夷の標的は ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ｡
Our next target is the spaceship terminal.
天人を召喚する
あの 忌まわしき塔を破壊し➡
We shall destroy that accursed tower that brings the Amanto
ﾔﾂらを 江戸から殲滅する！
and we shall purge them from Edo.
(桂)だが あれは世界の要…
容易には落ちまい｡
But the tower is a major world hub. It won't fall easily.
お前の力がいる 銀時｡
We need your strength, Gintoki.
おいおい
さっきから言ってるが ｵﾚは…｡
Come on. I've been telling you that I...
すでに我らに加担した お前に
断る道はないぞ｡
You're already an accomplice for helping us. You can't refuse us.
If you don't want to be treated as a terrorist, then come with me.
爆弾魔として
処断されたくなくば ｵﾚと来い！
(桂)迷うことは なかろう｡
There's no need to hesitate.
Your place was always with us.
もともと お前の居場所は
ここだったはずだ！
銀さん…｡
Gin...
(足音)
(蹴り倒す音)
御用改めである！
神妙にしろ 爆弾魔ども！
You're under arrest!
Come quietly, you terrorist scum!
(志士たち)真選組だ！
I-It's the Shinsengumi!
Oh no! Run away!
いかん！ 逃げろ！
Kill them all!
(土方)１人残らず 討ち取れ！
何なんですか あの人ら！
Wh-Wh-Who are those people?!
They're the Shinsengumi, the Armed Police.
武装警察 真選組｡
An elite anti-terrorist squad they send in to wipe out rebel elements!
反乱分子を 即時 処分する
特殊警察部隊だ！
やっかいなのに捕まったな｡
どうします？ ﾎﾞｽ｡
Those guys are really annoying.
What should we do, boss?
誰がﾎﾞｽだ！ お前が いちばん
やっかいなんだよ！
I'm not your freakin' boss!
And you're the annoying one!
ﾂﾞﾗ！ ﾎﾞｽなら私に任せるよろし！
善行でも悪行でも➡
Zura, if you need a boss, I'm your man!
"Whether you're doing something good or bad, be the boss." That's my motto!
やるからには大将やるのが
私の ﾓｯﾄｰよ！
ｵﾒｴは黙ってろ！ なに その
戦国大名みてえなﾓｯﾄｰ！
You shut up!
Your mottos sounds like something out of the mouth of a feudal warlord!
(土方)おい！
Hey.
There's no need to run. It's a nice fight.
逃げることはねえだろう？
せっかくのｹﾝｶだ 楽しもうや｡
Let's have some fun.
おいおい ｵﾒｴ ﾎﾝﾄに役人か？
Hey, are you really a public official?
I'm surprised you passed the interview.
よく 面接 通ったな｡
瞳孔が開いてんぞ｡
Your pupils are dilated.
人のこと言えた義理か？
You should talk, creep!
Coming from someone with eyes of a dead fish.
ﾃﾒｴ 死んだ魚のような
目しやがって！
いいんだよ いざというときには
きらめくから｡
It's all right. They sparkle during my close-ups.
ｳｿつくんじゃねえ！
Don't lie!
♪♪～
(土方)やるじゃねえか｡
You're pretty good.
Most people can't keep up with this transition.
この変化には 大抵の者は
ついてこれねえんだがな｡
That's dangerous. What would you do if it really hit me?
危ねえなぁ
本当に当たったら どうすんだよ｡
You idiot! I'm trying to hit you!
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！こちとら
斬るために ｹﾝｶしてんだ！
♪♪～
Mr. Hijikata, look out.
(沖田)土方さん 危ないですぜ｡
(発射音)
(銀時/土方)うおっ！
(爆発音)
You alive, Mr. Hijikata?
生きてやすかい？ 土方さん｡
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
おっ死ぬところだったぜ！
Moron, you coulda killed me!
Aw. I missed.
ﾁｯ しくじったか｡
What do you mean miss?! Hey! Look at me!
しくじったって ｱﾝﾀ！
おい！ こっち見ろ おいっ！
…で ﾔﾂらは？
Where are they?
(隊士)副長 この中です｡
Vice-chief, they're in here.
≪(土方)おい！ 出てきやがれ！
Hey, come on out!
≪(土方)ﾑﾀﾞな抵抗は やめな！
髪 増えてない…？
Stop your useless resistance!
Did you grow more hair?
≪(土方)ここは 15階だ｡
This is the fifteenth floor. There's no escape!
≪逃げ場なんて
どこにも ないんだよ！
そりゃ なんのﾏﾈだ？
(桂)時限爆弾だ｡
What are you doing?
It's a time bomb.
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ爆破のために
用意していたんだが➡
I was going to use it on the terminal, but I have no choice.
しかたあるまい…｡
ｺｲﾂを ﾔﾂらに お見舞いする！
I'll give those guys a little present.
その隙に みんな逃げろ｡
In the confusion, everyone run.
(志士)貴様！
桂さんに何をするか！
Jerk! What do you think you're doing to Katsura?!
桂 もう しまいにしようや｡
Katsura, let's put an end to this.
ﾃﾒｴが どんだけ 手 汚そうと➡
No matter how much you get your hands dirty,
死んでいった仲間は 喜ばねえし
時代も変わらねえ｡
our dead buddies won't be pleased, nor will times change.
これ以上 薄汚れんな！
Don't dirty them anymore.
薄汚れたのは 貴様だ 銀時！
You're the one who's dirty, Gintoki.
As soon as times changed, you went over to the other side.
時代が変わるとともに
ﾌﾜﾌﾜと変節しおって｡
武士たる者 己の信じた一念を
貫き通すものだ！
A warrior must stick to his beliefs.
…お膳立てされた武士道
貫いて どうするよ？
What's the point in standing up for beliefs that have been laid out for me?
そんなもんのために
また大事な仲間 失うつもりか！
Looking forward to losing your precious friends?
ｵﾚは もう そんなの ご免だ！
I don't want that anymore.
If it's my life on the line, I'll adhere to my own code.
どうせ 命 張るなら
ｵﾚはｵﾚの武士道を貫く｡
ｵﾚの美しいと思った生き方をし
ｵﾚの守りてぇもんを守る！
And I'll protect what I want to protect.
♪♪～
銀ちゃん これ いじくってたら
ｽｲｯﾁ押しちゃったよ｡
Gin...this thingy...I pushed the switch when I was fiddling with it.
悪夢だ｡
ﾍﾞﾀだな｡
What a nightmare.
How cliché.
(沖田)お～い 出てこ～い
ﾏｼﾞで撃っちゃうぞ～｡
Hey, come out. We're really going to fire this time.
土方さん 夕方のﾄﾞﾗﾏの再放送
始まっちゃいますぜ｡
Mr. Hijikata, our evening soap rerun is going to start soon.
やっべ｡ ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵ予約すんの忘れてた｡
Geez. I forgot to set my VCR.
(土方)さっさと済まそ｡
発射用意！
Let's get this over with. Prepare to fire!
(土方)発…｡
(銀時たち)しゃあ～!!
Fire!
(隊士)何やってんだ！ 止めろ！
Wh-What are you doing?! Stop them!
止めるなら
この爆弾 止めてくれ！
If you want to stop something, then stop this bomb, please!
爆弾処理班とかさぁ
なんか いるだろ おい！
You have a bomb squad, don't you?!
うわぁ！ 爆弾持ってんぞ ｺｲﾂ～！
He's got a bomb!
(隊士たち)うわ～！
Hold on! Hey, wait!
ちょ… ちょっと待てよ おい！
新八！ お前 機械 強いとか
言ってなかったっけか？
Shinpachi! Didn't you say that you were good with machines?!
か！ か か 勘違いですよ！
Y-Y-You're mistaken! Kagura, this is your fault to begin with!
元はといえば 神楽ちゃんの
せいなんだから なんとかして！
Do somethin'!
N-N-Naturally curly hair and bombs go well with each other!
て て… 天然ﾊﾟｰﾏと爆弾は
ﾜﾝｾｯﾄｱﾙよ！
よ！
よ よ… 横から いなりがﾎﾟﾛﾘ！
A-A-An inari sushi came out from the side!
A-A-An ethical society.
り… 倫理社会！
(神楽)い… いんぐりもんぐり！
I-I-Ingry Mongry?
り… ﾘｰﾁ ｲｯﾊﾟﾂ ﾂﾓ！
R-R-Reach, first-turn win, self-draw...
M-M-Momiji manju!!
も も も… もみじまんじゅう！
I-I-I don't want to have an affair!!
(神楽)う… 浮気じゃ 嫌よ！
よ よ 横井さん おかえりなさい！
W-W-Welcome back, Yokoi!!
い いつまで
やってんですか これぇ！
H-H-How long are we going to do this?!
A-A-Adrian!!
(神楽)え え… ｴｲﾄﾞﾘｱ～ﾝ！
って ｴｲﾄﾞﾘｱﾝって誰だよ!?
Who is Adrian anyway?! The game ends if you end it with "N"!
つうか ｢ん｣がついたら
終わりだろうが！
んっ？ あ！
わ～ あと10秒しかねえ！
Only 10 seconds left!
銀さん！ 窓！ 窓～！
無理！ もう死ぬ！
Gin! The window, the window!
Impossible! We're dead!
(神楽)銀ちゃん
歯 食いしばるね！
Gin, bite down on something.
はぁ～！
お おい！
Oh. Hey!
ほあちゃ～っ!!
あぁ～！
ぐわっ… ふんっ！
てやっ！
(爆発音)
ぎ… 銀さ～ん!!
G-Gin!
銀ちゃん さようなら～!!
Good-bye, Gin!
あぁ…｡
If you've got enough time to fantasize about your beautiful death,
((美しく 最期を
飾りつける暇があるなら➡
最期まで
美しく生きようじゃねえか))
why not just live beautifully to the end?
ﾌｯ…｡
(桂)美しい生き方だと？
Live life beautifully?
(桂)
あれの どこが美しいんだか…｡
What's so beautiful about that?
ﾌﾌﾌｯ…｡
I guess having a friend who never changes isn't such a bad thing, after all.
(桂)だが 昔の友人が
変わらずにいるっていうのも➡
悪くないものだな…｡
Hurry, Sogo!
(土方)早くしろ 総悟！
(沖田/土方)ﾄﾞﾗﾏの再放送～！
The soap opera rerun!
(沖田)ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘｾｰﾌ｡
よし！
We made it!
All right!
♪♪(ﾃﾚﾋﾞﾄﾞﾗﾏのﾃｰﾏ曲)
[A Tender Drama]
[There're only demons in the world, damn it!!]
[Starring Pinko Koizumi]
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)
この時間は 予定を変更して➡
[Special Report]
A bombing at the Ikedaya Hotel.
We interrupt this broadcast to bring you a special report.
報道特番を お送りします｡
現場の結野ｱﾅ！
Ketsuno is at the scene! Ketsuno! Ana!
(結野)はい 現場の結野です｡
(土方/沖田)おぉお～い!!
This is Ketsuno at the scene.
[Preview]
Shinpachi, you're the leader of an idol singer fan club?
You're just like what you look like: a four-eyed geek.
You're a pretty typical character, aren't you?
So is this old man one of your geeky friends?
The next episode...
"Keep a Promise Even If It Kills You."
[Idol Tsu Terakado Age 17. Currently on her first live tour!!]
[Her debut song "Your Mom is XX" is too dirty to be aired!!]
[Third Year, Class Z]
Third year, class Z, Ginpachi-sensei!
♪♪～
[Third Year, Class Z]
Stand! Bow! Take your seats!
(近藤)起立!! 礼！ 着席!!
OK everyone, open Gin Tama volume 1.
は～い
じゃあ 『銀魂』１巻 開いて｡
[MIND YOUR SUGAR LEVELS]
今日の授業では
｢ぎんたま｣の意味を解明したい｡
For today's lesson, I'd like to explain the meaning of "Gin Tama."
[Gin Tama]
え～ 誰か わかるﾔﾂ いる？
ぎんたまの意味｡
Does anyone know the meaning of "Gin Tama"?
(神楽)はい｡ 桂君の長髪がｼﾞｬﾏで
黒板が見えません｡
Here!
I can't see the black board because of Katsura's long hair.
ﾂﾞﾗ！ 髪切ってこいって
言ったろうが｡ もしくは とれ｡
Zura, I told you to go cut your hair or take it off.
先生… とれません｡
Sensei, I can't take it off.
Then remove it.
じゃあ はずせ｡
先生… 訴えますよ｡
Sensei, I'm so going to sue this school.
え～ 授業に戻るぞ｡
Let's get back to our lesson.
Sensei!
(沖田)先生！
Kagura, the exchange student, is eating her bento lunch in class.
留学生の神楽さんが早弁してます｡
しかも ｳｨﾝﾅｰを これみよがしに
見せつけています｡
She's totally flashing her wiener, too.
(神楽)先生
早弁じゃありません｡
Sensei, I'm not having early lunch.
私の国では ﾎﾟｯﾌﾟｺｰﾝとか食べながら
授業してました｡
In my country, I always had snacks like popcorn during class.
そうか… 帰れ 国に！
I see. Then go back to your country!
はい じゃあ 授業に戻る｡
OK, so back to the lesson...
Sensei!
(土方)先生！
ん？
授業中に ﾀﾊﾞｺはないと思います｡
I don't think you're supposed to smoking during class.
This isn't a cigarette.
これは ﾀﾊﾞｺじゃない
ﾚﾛﾚﾛｷｬﾝﾃﾞｨｰだ｡
It's a lollypop.
ﾚﾛﾚﾛｷｬﾝﾃﾞｨｰから 煙は出ません｡
Smoke doesn't come out from a lollypop.
それは
ものすごくﾚﾛﾚﾛしてるからだ｡
That's because I'm licking it so fast.
ｹﾞｯ！
今 言ったことは ﾃｽﾄに出るぞ｡
(終業のﾁｬｲﾑ)
What I just covered will be on the test.
ちゃんと ﾉｰﾄにとっとけ！ 以上｡
So you better be taking notes.  Dismissed!
(終業のﾁｬｲﾑ)
転校しよう…｡
I'm gonna transfer outta here.
[The End]
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～